do you guys know that in 2022 a blender
你们知道吗 在2022年 一台搅拌机
was downloaded 17 million times crazy
被疯狂下载了1700万次
number it's not the total number of
数字它不是总数量
users because some people are
用户 因为有些人
downloading every release in the year
一年中的每个版本都在下载
and then others are using a release from
然后其他人正在使用来自
years prior but the best guess of
几年前 但最好的猜测是
blender's total user size is about 10
Blender的总用户规模约为10
million 10 million blender users but I
一千万搅拌机用户 但我
now have to follow with some rather sad
现在不得不随之而来的是一些相当悲伤的事情
news only about 3600 of them are
新闻中只有3600人是
actually contributing to the blender
实际上是对搅拌机的贡献
Development Fund that means and this is
发展基金 这意味着这是
the scary bit if you were to fill the
如果你要填上
Yankee Stadium with 46,000 blender users
拥有4.6万名搅拌机用户的Yankee体育场
only about 17 of them would be
只有大约17个人会是
contributors now not only is this not a
贡献者现在不仅这不是一个
great look for the open-source world but
开源世界看起来很棒 但是
it means that blender is going to be
这意味着搅拌机将成为
developed slower than paid software like
开发速度慢于付费软件 如
I mentioned previously that the texture
我之前提到过 质地
painting features of blender are rather
搅拌机的涂装功能相当于
limited and old well they've wanted to
有限的和古老的 他们一直想
build proper PBR texture painting for
构建合适的PBR纹理绘制
years but they lack the funds to hire a
多年 但他们缺乏资金聘请一名
full-time developer the same applies to
全职开发人员同样适用于
the broken fire and fluid Simulator the
破碎的火焰和流体模拟器
video sequence editor the list goes on
视频序列编辑列表不胜枚举
and we could have all of these
我们可以拥有所有这些
improvements today if we only had the
今天的进步如果我们有
funds so last month I was at the blunder
所以上个月我犯了个大错
Institute speaking to Franchesco City
研究所与弗兰切斯科城对话
and he asked for my help to bring
他让我帮他把
awareness to this so I'm asking you
意识到了这一点 所以我问你
right now that's right right now donate
现在 就是现在 捐赠
if you're enjoying this series and you
如果你喜欢这部电视剧 而你
like blender then please pause this
就像搅拌机一样 请暂停这个
video right now and take 2 minutes to
立即播放视频 并花2分钟
sign up and pick a plan not only do you
签约并选择一个计划 不仅你
get to be one of the cool 17 people in
成为世界上最酷的17个人之一
the stadium that's donating but you'll
正在捐赠的体育场 但你会
know that the Amazing Story of blender
知道搅拌机的神奇故事吗？
gets to continue because of you and if
因为你才能继续 如果
you do join the Development Fund because
你加入发展基金是因为
of this video then please comment below
请在下面发表评论
with # jooin blender so that I can tally
用#Jooin搅拌机 这样我就可以打分了
up how much of an impact this little PSA
关于这个小小的PSA有多大的影响
and the series has had as a whole so
作为一个整体 这部电视剧已经有了
with that out of the way let's get on to
说到这里 让我们开始吧
the tutorial so how did you go with your
这个教程你是怎么做的？
homework did you take a stab at creating
作业你有没有尝试过创造
the plate did you do it or did you wait
盘子你是做了还是等了？
for me to show you the answer hope you
对于我给你看的答案 希望你
did uh if you didn't you're only
有没有 如果你没有 你只是
cheating yourself as the teacher say um
就像老师说的那样自欺欺人
but no seriously give it a shot if you
但不 认真地试一试 如果你
haven't already I do think it helps you
不是吗？我觉得这对你有帮助
uh helps you to learn but if you don't
呃 帮助你学习 但如果你不
want to can't stop you uh but I'll show
想阻止不了你 呃 但我会证明的
you now how I created this plate so
你现在知道我是如何制作这个车牌的吗？
first of all um I load in the image
首先 嗯 我在图像中加载
reference first um and I haven't shown
参考第一个 嗯 我还没有展示
you how to do that yet so I'll show you
你还不知道怎么做 所以我来教你
now if you go to the top of the screen
现在 如果您转到屏幕顶部
until the cursor changes on that line
直到该行上的光标发生变化
there just right click and then say
点击鼠标右键 然后说
vertical split and then I now get two
垂直分割 然后我现在得到两个
duplicate Windows this second window I
复制Windows此第二个窗口
can now make any other window type so
现在可以将任何其他窗口类型设置为
the one I'm looking for is image editor
我要找的那个人是图片编辑
now go image and open so this is the
现在开始成像并打开 这是
image we're going to use it's one from
我们要使用的图像是来自
polygon because it's actually one of our
因为它实际上是我们的一个
models it's a real ceramic plate that we
模型这是一个真正的陶瓷板 我们
photos scanned turned into a model but I
扫描的照片变成了一个模型 但我
thought it's also just a really nice
我觉得这也是一个很好的
simple modeling exercise for beginners
为初学者提供简单的建模练习
so why not model off of that okay so
所以为什么不效仿呢？好的 所以
shift a because you got to start with
换个班 因为你得从
something now a lot of you probably
现在你们中的许多人可能会有一些
started with a cylinder um and that's a
从一个圆柱体开始 这是一个
fine way to go about it but I know from
这样做很好 但我知道
experience that the cylinder's got a top
体验圆柱体有一个顶部
face on it that we don't need and then
面对我们不需要的东西 然后
the normals have to be flipped and you
法线必须翻转 而你
have to deal with the size and I find
必须处理好尺寸问题 我发现
it's actually just easier to start with
实际上 从一开始就很容易
a circle and then build out from that so
一个圆圈 然后从那里建立起来 所以
the circle settings obviously want to
圆圈设置显然想要
turn the radius down to be yeah just I
把半径调小到是的就是我
mean I think a plate is roughly the size
我的意思是 我认为一个盘子的大小大致是
of like two doughnut widths anyway like
就像两个甜甜圈的宽度一样
roughly 24 30 cm whatever so anyway a
大约24 30厘米 不管怎么说 所以不管怎样
radius of around uh 12 CM now the
半径大约12厘米现在
vertices that's the resolution of your
顶点 这是你的分辨率
mesh right now you might remember when
现在你可能还记得什么时候
we did the dut when we added the Taurus
当我们添加了金牛座的时候 我们做到了这一点
I said it's good to start with a low
我说从低谷开始是很好的
poly mesh to begin with because it's
多边形网格 因为它是
easier to add detail than it is to try
添加细节比尝试更容易
to take it away later and that's true
以后再把它拿走 这是真的
and it's good advice for like organic
对于有机食品来说 这是个好建议
flowy shapes but in this case I know
飘逸的形状 但在这种情况下 我知道
that looking at the reference it's got
看着它得到的参考资料
bevels like tight bevels here and here
斜面就像这里和这里的紧密斜面
and it's going to be a lot easier to
这样做会容易得多
control that if I just use the bevel
如果我只用斜角来控制它
tool as we model rather than trying to
工具作为我们的模型 而不是试图
use a subsurf modifier later which is
稍后使用细分曲面修改器 它是
all to say that the resolution of the
总而言之 美国政府的决议
circle that we start with I actually
我们从那个圈子开始 实际上我
want to be the final representation so
想成为最终的代表 所以
essentially this needs to be as round
从本质上讲 这需要是一样的圆
and high resolution as it needs to be
以及所需的高分辨率
until so that I won't see any jaggedness
直到我看不到任何锯齿状
in the final model so I actually went
在最终的模型中 所以我实际上
with a 100 vertices which is quite High
有100个顶点 这是相当高的
poly but we have got the camera really
保利 但我们真的有相机
close to it so I think it makes sense
接近它 所以我认为这是有意义的
okay so in edit mode make sure you're in
好的 所以在编辑模式下 确保您处于
verticy select mode I've done recording
垂直选择模式我已经录制好了
so many times I can't remember when I've
很多次我都不记得我什么时候
uh actually taught something or not but
呃 不管是不是真的教了什么 但是
you can swap in and out of these modes
您可以切换进入和退出这些模式
by the way by hitting uh the one two and
顺便说一句 通过敲击呃1 2和
three key so one for vertices two for
三个关键点 因此一个用于顶点 两个用于
Edge and then three for face select okay
边 然后三个用于面选择OK
so with verticy select I'm going to
因此 通过垂直选择 我将
start by creating this lip that goes up
从创造这个向上的嘴唇开始
so e and then Zed to lock it on the Zed
因此 E和ZED将其锁定在ZED上
axis to about there I mean we don't have
轴心大约在那里 我的意思是我们没有
measurements but that looks like it
尺寸 但看起来就是这样
could be plausible and I think it's on a
可能是合理的 我认为这是在一个
slight angle very slight so I'm going to
微微的角度非常微微所以我要
scale out just by hitting s all right
横向扩展 只要击中S就行了
now for this next part of the lip I'm
现在 对于嘴唇的下一部分 我是
going to hit e to extrude extrude again
要按e再挤
but I don't want to uh move it anywhere
但我不想 呃 把它移到任何地方
I want to do it exactly where it is but
我想原地踏步 但是
then scale it out out so right click and
然后向外扩展 然后右键单击并
then s to scale out
然后S向外扩展
all right and it's a good idea also to
好的 这也是一个好主意
just zoom out and see in proportion to
只需缩小并按比例查看即可
the plate is that lip about the right
车牌就是右边的那个嘴唇
size I think it is that's pretty good
尺码 我想是的 很好
and now I'm going to do another lip on
现在我要再做一次唇彩
the other side just going up so e z to
另一边只是往上走 所以Ez到
about there that's pretty good and then
关于那里 这是相当好的 然后
s to scale out as
S将横向扩展为
well okay awesome now uh when you add in
好的 好的 现在 当你加上
a circle it doesn't come with a face by
一个没有脸的圆圈
default so if we go into wireframe mode
默认设置 因此如果我们进入线框模式
which also uh you can swap sorry not
还有 呃 你可以跟我交换抱歉 不
that mode y frame mode you can swap in
模式y帧模式 您可以换入该模式
and out of these modes at the top here
在上面的这些模式中
by holding down the Zed key so solid
通过牢牢按住Zed键
View and YF frame I usually just quickly
查看和YF帧I通常只是快速
flip in between those um like that all
在那些之间 嗯 就像那样
right so if I hold down alt and click on
对 所以如果我按住Alt键并点击
this line you can see there's no face in
你可以看到这条线上没有脸
the middle because wherever there is a
中间是因为哪里有
face is there should be like this orange
脸应该是这样的橙色
tint so when I alt click here I don't
所以当我点击此处时 我不会
see the orange tint which means I need
看到橙色 这意味着我需要
to have a face so F to create a face now
要使面如此F 现在要创建面
we need some bevels okay so we need a
我们需要一些斜角 好的 所以我们需要一个
bevel that goes here another one that
这个倒角放在这里又一个倒角
goes here and another one that goes here
放在这里 另一个放在这里
so we did that when we uh added the
所以我们这样做时 呃 我们添加了
sprinkle and the hotkey for it is contrl
洒水 快捷键是控制
B but I don't want to just create like
B但我不想只是像这样创造
the same uh bevel here and then do
同样的 呃 这里 然后做斜面
another one here and then another one
另一个在这里 然后另一个
here I can do them all at the same time
在这里 我可以同时完成所有这些操作
so if I hit alt and shift and then
所以如果我按下Alt和Shift键 然后
clicked on these lines if I did contrl B
如果我控制了B 点击了这些行
now I would get a bevel everywhere but
现在我到处都能看到斜面 但是
the problem is is that I'm also getting
问题是 我也得到了
the bevel on the lines that are going uh
线条上的斜面正在进行呃
this way right like uh these lines which
这条路就像 呃 这些线
is not what I want but it doesn't know
不是我想要的 但它不知道
that I don't want them there because
我不想让他们在那里 因为
those are edges that are also selected
这些边也是选定的边
right this uh this line that goes like
对 这 呃 这句话是这样的
that so what you need to use is just a
所以您需要使用的只是一个
different tool so instead of verticy
不同的工具 而不是垂直
Select mode I'm going to use Edge select
选择模式我将使用边选择
mode and now when I hit uh alt click on
模式 现在当我点击Alt时 点击
that line and then shift alt click on
那行 然后按下Shift Alt键
this line it's only selecting those
这行它只选择那些
edges and not the edges in between which
而不是它们之间的边
means now when I do contrl B to create
意思是现在当我控制B来创建
that bevel I'm getting the bevel just
我得到的那个斜面只是
where I want it on those three uh three
我想把它放在那三个呃三个
edges all right now the tightness of
好的边缘现在的紧密性
that it's pretty tight but does need to
它很紧 但确实需要
be a little bit higher poly so I'm just
稍微高一点 所以我只是
mousing sorry scrolling up on my uh on
鼠标 抱歉 在我的额上滚动
my mouse to about there that's good and
我的鼠标放在那里很好 而且
now solid view great pretty good all
现在立体视图很好 很好
right getting there now we got a paper
刚到那里 我们就有一份报纸
thin plate we don't want that so for
我们不想要这么薄的盘子
thickness I'm hoping most of you got
厚度我希望你们大多数人都有
this right but it's our old trusty
这是对的 但这是我们的老信得过
modifier the solidifier modifier that we
修改器我们使用的固化剂修改器
used previously it's too thick by
以前用过的太厚了
default um I I think I went with
默认情况下 嗯 我想我选择了
04 like that all right and then because
04像这样 好吧 然后因为
I want to do a bevel on this edge here I
我想在这条边上做个倒角
can't do it unless this solidify
除非这个固化 否则我不能这么做
modifier is applied so drop down and
修饰符已应用 因此下拉菜单和
then hit apply and now in edit mode I've
然后点击Apply 现在处于编辑模式
got both of those edges so again holding
得到了这两个边缘 所以再次握住
down alt and shift alt click on those
按下Alt键和Shift键并单击这些按钮
two edges and now I'm going to do
两条边 现在我要做的是
another bevel right here contrl + B and
另一个斜面就在这里Ctrl+B和
pull it out now you'll see that it it
现在把它拿出来 你就会看到它了
reaches a point where they start to
到达一个点 在那里他们开始
overlap and that's not good I don't want
重叠 这不好 我不想要
that I want it to be I do actually want
我希望它成为我真正想要的
it to be a complete round form like
它是一个完整的圆形 就像
really like essentially that but you can
真的很喜欢 但你可以
see I can't really get it exactly right
看 我真的不能完全正确地做好它
where they're just like meeting in the
在那里他们就像在
middle so there's actually when you're
中间 所以实际上当你在
in certain States in blunder you'll see
在大错特错的某些州 你会看到
at the bottom of your screen along uh
在你屏幕的底部沿着呃
let me just do this along this line here
让我沿着这条线来做这个
you can see you've got a number of uh
你可以看到你有一些呃
shortcuts that it lists and one of them
它列出的快捷键和其中之一
says C for clamp overlap and currently
表示夹具重叠 当前为C
it's listed as off so if I oh dear let's
它被列为关闭 所以如果我 哦 亲爱的 让我们
guel that if I uh when I hit control B
如果我 呃 当我按下控制键B时
whilst I'm in this state if I hit C it
当我处于这种状态时 如果我按下C它
will turn clamp overlap on which means
将打开夹具重叠 这意味着
it will only bevel until the point that
它只会摇摇欲坠 直到
the edges touch and then it will stop
边缘接触 然后它就会停止
and that is exactly what I want so I'll
这正是我想要的 所以我会
just click to confirm and now we have a
只需点击确认 现在我们就有了
plate but when you're modeling something
车牌 但当你在做模特的时候
like this it's very common if you're
就像这样 如果你是
doing like extrusions and then you're
就像挤压一样 然后你就会
canceling the extrus and then you're
取消临时演员 然后你就会
scaling out you can end up with vertices
向外扩展可能最终得到折点
on top of vertices and in fact when we
在顶点的顶部 事实上当我们
did that bevel clamping thing I think
我想是不是那个夹角的东西
what it's done is it's got two edges and
它所做的是它有两个边和
they've now merged the vertices in the
它们现在已经合并了
middle but they the um it's sharing the
但是他们 嗯 它在分享
same space so whenever you've got two
同样的空间 所以当你有两个
vertices in exactly the same space you
位于与您完全相同的空间中的顶点
can have like artifacting that will
可以有像人工制品这样的东西
occur later on so after I model
之后发生 所以在我建模之后
something like this I just go into uh
像这样的事情 我只是进入 呃
edit mode I select everything by hitting
编辑模式我通过点击选择所有内容
a and then I want to find all of those
A然后我想找到所有那些
vertices that are uh accidentally in the
呃 偶然出现在
wrong place and then hit M and then I
打错了地方 然后按了M 然后我
want to say merge by distance and now
我想说按距离和现在合并
you can see on the bottom of my screen
你可以在我屏幕的底部看到
look at that it merged 300 vertices I've
看它合并了300个顶点
modeled this pled a few times sometimes
有时会对此进行几次建模
it it deleted like 400 vertices usually
它通常会删除400个折点
it deletes 100 um evidently when I was
它明显删除了100um 当我是
uh yeah doing the Extrusion and then
嗯 是的 做挤压 然后
cancelling it I think I maybe did it a
取消了 我想我可能做了一个
few times so we had like three rings
几次 所以我们有三个戒指
essentially in the exact same place so
基本上在同一个地方 所以
that's why you do that step because if
这就是为什么你要这么做 因为如果
we didn't then you would have that and
我们没有 然后你就会有那个
you wouldn't know until you see
你不会知道 直到你看到
artifacts later on all right but that's
文物稍后好吧 但那是
it we now have a wonderful looking plate
如果我们现在有了一个很棒的车牌
and we can uh close that oh yeah I
我们可以 呃 关闭它 哦 是的 我
should show you how to close the the
应该会向您展示如何关闭
window um so when you are closing
窗户嗯 所以当你关门的时候
something you can go here on this Edge
你可以在这个边缘上找到一些东西
and you can right click and then say
你可以点击鼠标右键然后说
join areas the other way is if you go to
加入区域的另一种方式是如果您要访问
the top right hand corner of the screen
屏幕的右上角
you get this little like targeting
你会发现这有点像是瞄准
cursor and then if you click and drag
光标 然后如果您单击并拖动
left or right that will also merge it's
左或右也会合并它的
just that's how you used to create
你以前就是这么创造的
Windows and blender you can also drag
窗口和搅拌器 您还可以拖动
out from it and that will split the view
从那里出来 那将会分裂视线
um that's it's kind of an old habit of
嗯 那是一种古老的习惯
mind but most people just prefer to like
介意 但大多数人只是更喜欢
until the cursor changes right click and
直到光标更改 然后单击鼠标右键
then say that but I still do that
那就这么说吧 但我还是会这么做
sometimes and then I forget I'm doing a
有时候 然后我忘了我在做一个
tutorial and I have to explain it all
教程和我必须解释这一切
right so the plate um we want to make it
好的 那么这个盘子 嗯 我们想做
smooth so right click shade smooth and
平滑 因此右键单击阴影平滑和
the reason we have flickering right here
我们在这里有闪烁的原因
is the top of our plate is uh
我们盘子里最顶端的是呃
overlapping with the countertop so we
与台面重叠 所以我们
just need to move this up slightly so
只要把这个稍微往上移一点就行了
that it's not doing that um and if you
它不是这样做的 嗯 如果你
actually go underneath your countertop
实际上是在你的台面下
this is usually a very easy way to
这通常是一种非常简单的方法
quickly make it so that um it's touching
快点做 这样 嗯 它就会触动
you just have a little bit of overlap
你只是有一点重叠
and then um yeah then it it looks
然后 嗯 是的 然后它看起来
plausible awesome we have our plate um
看似很棒 我们有我们的车牌
now if I move out here you can see this
现在如果我搬到这里 你可以看到这个
this big giant arrow thing this is our
这支巨大的箭是我们的
camera and it's just too big the
摄像头太大了
visualization of it is so big that I've
它的视觉效果是如此之大 以至于我
got lines in the way and I just I don't
线挡住了我的路 我只是我不
like it um it's actually a pretty good
喜欢它 嗯 它实际上是一个很好的
scale for a normal scene which is you
缩放到正常场景 即您自己
know usually tens or hundreds of meters
知道通常有几十米或几百米
but we're so small that this camera is
但我们太小了 所以这台相机
just too big so in the camera tab go to
只是太大了 所以在相机选项卡中转到
Viewpoint display and then just turn
视点显示 然后只需转动
down the size right um and I'll go for
把尺码降到合适的 嗯 我要
yeah like 10% of what it was to about a
是啊 大概是它的10%
0.1 okay great so what we want to do now
好的 很好 那么我们现在要做的是
is start laying out the scene so first
是先开始布置场景
and foremost I'm going to go into
最重要的是 我要谈到
looking through my camera view and I
看着我的相机视野 我
want to get the camera placement right
我想要正确放置摄像头
so hitting shift titer key to put me
所以按下Shift滴定键就能把我
into uh fly View and then just scrolling
进入 呃 飞行视图 然后滚动
down so that you get really small
这样你就会变得很小
movements not that small to scroll up a
移动不是那么小 向上滚动
little bit all right and then I'm using
一点好吧 然后我就用
q and E to just change the height of the
Q和E 只需更改
camera to be roughly where I want it all
相机大概就是我想要的一切
right so I'm going to have a stack of
好的 所以我会有一堆
donuts so I'm going to have like one
所以我想要一个甜甜圈
here one here one here so um I'm just
这里一个 这里一个 所以 嗯 我只是
making room for that essentially I
为此腾出空间本质上是我
shouldn't use this annotation tool it's
不应该使用这个注释工具 它是
uh it's being replaced in blender like
呃 它在搅拌机里被取代了 就像
the new grease pencil is going to be
这支新的油铅笔将是
pretty amazing um but anyways it's the
很神奇 嗯 但不管怎样 这是
old old annotation tool so uh yeah let's
老旧的批注工具 所以 嗯 好的 让我们
start stacking some donuts so selecting
开始堆放一些甜甜圈 这样就可以选择
the base donut and then shift selecting
按下底座甜甜圈 然后按Shift键选择
the icing I'm going to duplicate that by
我要复制的糖衣是
shift d and then moving it up along the
按下Shift键 然后沿
Zed axis until they start to touch now
ZED轴 直到他们现在开始接触
there is actually some new snapping
实际上有一些新的抓拍
Tools in blender that is uh pretty handy
搅拌机里的工具 呃 非常方便
but from experience having tried it for
但从我尝试过的经验来看
this there's so many like little little
这里面有那么多像小小的
pieces of sprinkle and everything that
零星的东西和所有的东西
you're going to have overlapping anyway
不管怎样 你都会有重叠
because Donuts are quite spongy so they
因为甜甜圈很松软 所以他们
would be you know it would be plausible
那就是你知道这是可能的
that it would be like kind of squishing
这就像是一种挤压
the sprinkle so it's okay to have some
洒上了 所以吃点也没关系
clipping so something like that is okay
剪裁 所以这样的事情是可以的
now I'm going to do another donut so
现在我要做另一个甜甜圈
shift d again move it up along the Zed
再次按Shift d将其沿Zed向上移动
axis uh to about there and I want to
轴心 呃 大约在那里 我想
make it an interesting stack not just
让它成为一个有趣的堆栈 而不仅仅是
like a straight stack so I'll move these
就像一堆直的东西 所以我会把这些
around so that we've got kind of a like
所以我们有一种类似于
an S shape like that all right duplicate
一个S的形状 就像那个一样 好的复制品
these again so this is going to be a
这些 所以这将是一个
stack of
堆叠的
four like so
四个这样的
and then this one I'll pull back this
然后这个 我会把这个拉回来
way rotate that go
用旋转的方式去走
down all right and pull it back a little
好的 把它往后拉一点
bit okay lovely now looking from the
好的 现在看起来很可爱
camera you can see a pattern that has
摄像机 你可以看到一个图案 它有
emerged um so you can see this is the
出现了 嗯 所以你可以看到这是
same as this is the same as this and the
与此相同 与此相同 并且
eye is very good at detecting pattern so
眼睛很擅长检测图案 所以
that's going to be a very big uh deal
这将是一件非常大的事情 呃
breaker for the viewer they're going to
对于观众来说 他们将是一个断路器
notice that and it's just going to make
注意到这一点 它就会让
the picture look worse so with each
情况看起来更糟 每一次都是如此
donut selected one by one I going to hit
一个接一个地挑选甜甜圈我要砸
R and then tap Zed and that's going to
然后点击Zed 这将是
just rotate along the Zed axis but you
只需沿着ZED轴旋转 但您
can see if I just tap Zed that that that
我可以看看我是不是点击了Zed
uh axis that I I put it on a little bit
呃 轴 我 我把它放在上面一点
like just tilted it it's now uh like
就像刚刚倾斜了一下 现在呃就像
reverse the Tilt because I'm rotating
反转倾斜 因为我在旋转
along the Zed but what you can do is you
但你能做的是你自己
can rotate it along its original axis by
可以通过以下方式沿其原始轴旋转
not tapping Zed once but twice okay and
不是敲打Zed一次而是两次好的
you can see that the line has now
你可以看到 这条线现在已经
changed a little bit because that's
稍微改变了一下 因为那是
putting us now into the local Zed axis
让我们现在进入当地的ZED轴
so the original uh rotation of that
所以它最初的 呃 旋转
donut it's the Zed axis on that one not
甜甜圈 那是ZED轴 不是
the scene one so yeah that's the way I
第一场戏 所以耶 我就是这样
will do it um and I just want to rotate
我会做的 嗯 我只是想轮流
it until I get a different pattern so
直到我得到不同的图案 所以
now I've got these little wavy shapes
现在我有了这些波浪形的小东西
that's good now this one I'm going to
很好 现在我要做的就是
tap r and then Zed and Z again so it's
点击r 然后再点击Zed和Z 这样它就是
the uh the local axes that's pretty good
呃 当地的斧头 这很好
and then this one I'll do the same thing
然后这一次我会做同样的事情
r z z and just move it a little bit that
然后把它稍微移动一下
way all right and now it's a lot less
好的 现在少了很多
predictable cool and now the same thing
可预见的酷 现在是同样的事情
for this one so I'm going to do a stack
对于这个 所以我要做一个堆栈
of three so four and then three on this
三个 所以四个 然后三个
one so shift d
一个So Shift d
Zed and just coming in here this isn't
泽德和刚进来的这不是
hard this is just um it's just a little
这很难 只是 嗯 只是有点
finicky right um it would be good
挑剔的对吧 嗯 那会很好
actually if you could use motion sorry
事实上 如果你可以使用运动 对不起
not motion like a simulation Blended
不是像混合模拟那样的运动
does have rigid body tools but it's
确实有刚体工具 但它
again if we had more uh funding from
再说一次 如果我们有更多的呃资金来自
some people we could improve it because
有些人我们可以改进它 因为
the rigid body tools are pretty janky
刚体工具相当简陋
they don't work well for small objects
它们对小物体不起作用
and it's very fiddly to set up but I've
它的设置非常麻烦 但我已经
seen other tools plugins that people
看到了其他工具插件 人们
have made for like Unreal Engine where
做了像虚幻引擎一样的
placing objects is actually a simulation
放置对象实际上是一种模拟
so you just drawer across the plane and
所以你只需在飞机上抽屉
you could have like donuts just spawn in
你可能会像甜甜圈一样产卵
and like tumble on each other um and it
就像摔倒在彼此身上 嗯 它
just means that you don't have a lot of
只是意味着你没有太多的
this finicky uh hand placing of stuff
这种挑剔的呃手工摆放的东西
but for probably for a simple scene like
但对于像这样简单的场景来说
this I would probably hand place the
我可能会把这个放在
donuts anyway because you can finesse it
不管怎么说都是甜甜圈 因为你可以巧妙地
a lot better than you would in a a
比你在一个
simulation anyway
无论如何都要进行模拟
um all right so just like before making
嗯 好的 就像之前做的那样
it trying to yeah try and make it look
它试着 试着让它看起来
interesting as interesting as I can move
有趣 就像我能移动的那样有趣
this one closer that's pretty good and
这个更近一点 很好 而且
then so that we don't have the repeating
这样我们就不会有重复的
shapes r z
形状r z
z like that and that's pretty good
Z就像这样 这很好
actually uh this one it's a little bit
实际上 呃 这个有点小
further okay move that a little bit more
进一步 好的 再往前移一点
all right there we
好了 我们到了
go uh oh did I not hit
去啊 哦 我是不是没撞到
hang on did I Z okay I thought maybe I
等等 我是不是还好 我想也许我
didn't uh tap Zed twice but evidently I
呃 不是两次敲击Zed 但显然我
did it's just it's got this weird gap
是不是因为它有一个奇怪的缺口
which I going to have to close now
我现在要结束它了
okay sorry if you can hear traffic I am
好的 对不起 如果你能听到我在堵车
right next to a road I thought hey I
就在一条路上 我想 嘿 我
need an office why don't I get an office
我需要一间办公室 为什么不给我一间办公室
right next to a busy road with
紧挨着一条繁忙的道路
glass but I'll be moving out of here
玻璃 但我会搬出这里
soon planning to move country if I can
如果可以的话 我很快就会计划搬到别的国家去
I won't say where I'm moving to no I'm
我不会说我要搬到哪里去不 我要去
planning to move uh to the United States
计划搬到呃美国去
actually looking to get a Visa because
实际上是想拿到签证 因为
uh I want to move to La La it's where
我想搬到拉拉去 就是那里
all the other YouTubers are and uh I
所有其他YouTube用户都是 呃 我
don't know every time I go there I come
我不知道每次去那里我都会来
back with like a bunch of ideas and yeah
带着一堆点子回来 是的
so I'm moving if I can still waiting for
所以我要搬家 如果我还能等的话
a visa to be approved but uh we'll we'll
签证有待批准 但我们会 我们会
see all right so I'm just making small
看吧 好吧 我只是在做小事
adjustments here and there all right and
这里和那里的调整都是正确的
the final donut that I will create take
我将创造的最后一个甜甜圈
this uh I'll just take this bottom one
这个 呃 我就要这个最下面的
shift d and I'm going to make a doughnut
Shift d和我要做一个甜甜圈
which is going to be um like rotated to
这将是嗯 就像旋转到
the camera a little bit so yeah let's
相机有一点 所以好的 让我们
move on one axis said here and it's just
在这里所说的一个轴上移动 它只是
going to be like this because this is a
会是这样的 因为这是一个
much more readable shape that tells you
可读性更强的图形告诉您
exactly what it is because I mean this
它到底是什么 因为我是说
these Stacks could make you believe that
这些堆栈可能会让你相信
maybe it's bagels or like little mini
可能是百吉饼或者迷你面包
cakes or something like that so having
蛋糕或类似的东西 所以有
this one rotated towards the camera
这一张转到了镜头前
makes it very clear that these are
非常清楚地表明 这些是
donuts awesome all right cool now uh it
甜甜圈太棒了 好吧 现在很酷
wasn't supposed to be that we have round
不应该是我们有回合
sprinkles on this side and then long
洒在这一边 然后再长
sprinkles on this side uh that's just
洒在这边 呃 那只是
because we were duplicating shapes but
因为我们在复制形状 但是
because we've done this with geometry
因为我们已经用几何学做了这个
nodes it's really simple to just swap it
节点只需交换它就可以非常简单
out to be something else so this one
是其他的 所以这一次
here I actually just want it to be the
在这里 我实际上只是想让它成为
long sprinkles so in your geometry node
在您的几何体节点中有较长的散布
dropdown click long sprinkles and there
下拉点击长长的散布 然后在那里
we go just just swapped it out and now I
我们刚刚把它换掉了 现在我
can mix it up a bit I can say this one
我可以把它混在一起 我可以说这一句
here I want to have round sprinkles uh
在这里我想要圆形的喷洒 嗯
this one at the bottom I don't want to
底部的这一张我不想
have any sprinkles so it's just a bare
有任何的洒 所以它只是一个光秃秃的
dut cuz those do exist right uh this one
Dut因为那些确实存在 呃 这一个
I'll I'll say round sprinkles on there
我会 我会说 在那里撒上圆形的
and then I'll make this one long
然后我会把这个做得很长
sprinkles yeah and then maybe this one
撒一些是的 然后可能是这个
I'll delete it as well so we get like
我也会把它删除 这样我们就像
two plain ones that's pretty good and
两个普通的 很不错的 而且
there's a big gap here I don't know why
这里有一个很大的差距 我不知道为什么
how did that happen what did I do wrong
那是怎么回事？我做错了什么？
evidently I made a big
很明显 我做了一个很大的
gap by the way here's a tip if if you
顺便提一下 这是个小贴士 如果你
double so if you just hit R you're in
双倍 所以如果你只按R键 你就进入了
like like tilt mode but if you tap
就像倾斜模式 但如果你点击
double r so you tap r twice it's now in
双R 所以你点击R两次 它现在在
track ball rotation mode which depending
跟踪球旋转模式取决于
on your view can be what you want so I
在你看来可以是你想要的 所以我
just go there double tap r and I just
只要去那里 按两下r 我就
rotate it towards the camera a little
将它朝相机方向旋转一点
bit and pull it
咬住它 然后拉它
down maybe that's what I did maybe I
也许这就是我所做的 也许我
lowered the bottom donuts and then the
把底部的甜甜圈放低 然后
top ones didn't go with
排名靠前的不适合
it if you wanted to you could actually
如果你想的话你实际上可以
parent the donuts to each other other so
让甜甜圈互相为人父母 这样
that when you rotate or move one on the
当你旋转或移动一个在
bottom then it moves the one on the top
底部 然后移动顶部的那个
but I don't think it's really necessary
但我不认为真的有必要
and it can be a little bit hard to work
而且工作起来可能有点难
with as well so yeah oh they're now
也是如此耶 哦 他们现在是
touching I got to move
抚摸我 我得走了
apart yeah something like
分开 是的 就像这样
that awesome now the countertop I'm
太棒了 现在我在台面上
going to scale this out until the edges
我要向外扩展 直到边缘
of the countertop like this Edge that is
像这样的台面边缘就是
here and then this Edge that are here I
在这里 然后这里的边缘我
just outside of the frame because I
就在画框外面 因为我
camera I mean we are going to add a a
摄像机 我的意思是我们要添加一个
camera animation so that it goes down
相机动画 这样它就会下降
but we're not going to be like doing a
但我们不会像做一个
360 pan of the duts so we're not going
360平底锅的DUT所以我们不去
to be able to see the rest of the scene
为了能够看到场景的其余部分
so we don't need a kitchen countertop
所以我们不需要厨房台面
that stretches all out this way uh it's
一直延伸到这里 呃 这是
just a waste of resources um so we're
只是浪费资源 嗯 所以我们
just going to literally just stop at the
只是从字面上说就停在
edges of where the camera can see I used
相机可以看到的边缘我用过
to think when I was starting 3D that
想想当我开始3D的时候
that's like lazy but now I'm like no
这就像是懒惰 但现在我说不
that's like how you use your resources
这就像你如何使用你的资源
properly otherwise you end up doing
正确的做法 否则你最终会做
stuff that nobody ever sees um which is
没人见过的东西 嗯 这是
actually a pretty common problem in the
实际上 这是一个很常见的问题
industry um people over engineer models
行业 嗯 人超过工程师模型
and things just in case the camera needs
还有一些东西 以防摄像机需要
to be close and it never does and then
离得很近 但它永远不会 然后
yeah anyway now I do want a backsplash
好的 不管怎么说 现在我真的想要一个背影
for this so I'm just going to duplicate
对于这个 所以我要复制
the bottom plane here so shift d pull it
底部平面在这里 所以Shift d拉动它
out uh to you know roughly there and
据你所知 大概在那里
then I'm going to hit R and then X so
然后我要按R键 然后按X键
I'm rotating it along the x-axis and
我沿着x轴旋转它
then just holding down control to snap
然后只需按住Ctrl键即可抓取
it to the nearest 5° increment and in
到最接近的5°增量 并在
the top left hand corner of my screen
我屏幕的左上角
I'm just looking for 9
我只是在找9
and there it is so I do a single click
这就是它 所以我只需点击一下
I'll move this up like so and now we
我会像这样把这件事提前 现在我们
have a backsplash and the final thing
有一个后遗症和最后一件事
we'll do before moving on to the next
在进入下一个之前我们会这样做的
tutorial is create some different
教程是创建一些不同的
doughnut colors now you could actually
甜甜圈的颜色现在你实际上可以
do the same thing as we did uh for the
做和我们做的一样的事情 呃
sprinkles and create that random through
散布并创造出随机的穿透
color ramp option for this the trouble I
针对此问题的色带选项
found with doing it for the doughnut
为甜甜圈做这件事
icings is that you can sometimes just
结冰就是有时你可以
end up with a bad batch where you've got
最后得到的是一批不好的东西
like a string of like yellow donuts and
就像一串黄色的甜甜圈
you can't change it because there's no
你不能改变它 因为没有
sample option for the the random thing
随机事物的示例选项
so I find it's better if you haven't got
所以我觉得如果你没有
enough objects to instead just manually
足够的对象 只需手动
set up the colors um and it also just
设置颜色UM 它也只是
allows you allows you to finesse it as
允许您将其设置为
as more of an artist so a long way to
作为一名艺术家 还有很长的路要走
say we're going to create different
假设我们将创造不同的
materials for each of the different
每种不同类型的材料
icings so the one that's already there
冰层 所以已经在那里的那个
we'll just call it pink
我们就叫它粉色吧
icing and now um so I definitely want
糖霜 现在 嗯 所以我肯定想要
that one to be pink which means these
那件是粉色的 这意味着这些
ones that are directly behind it I
紧随其后的是
definitely want to be a different color
我当然想换个颜色
so I'm going to click the little uh
所以我要点击这个小的呃
number to make it a single user and I'll
号码 使其成为单一用户 我将
call this one blue icing and then the
把这个叫做蓝色糖衣 然后是
color I'm going to make it a kind of an
颜色我要把它变成一种
aaish color let's go into material
Aaish颜色 让我们来看看材料
select there we go this one here I'm
选择这里我们开始这一个我在这里
going to make it a yellow icing so
我要把它变成黄色的糖衣
clicking the little number next to it
点击它旁边的小数字
there we go yellow
我们走到黄色了
icing and then about there that's good
结冰 然后就在那里 这很好
and then this one at the top I'm going
然后这个在顶端的我要
to make it chocolate icing click the
要使其成为巧克力糖衣 请点击
little
一点儿
number chocolate icing let's go
数字巧克力糖衣我们走吧
Brown yeah yeah it's like how saturated
棕色是的是的它就像是多么饱和
how warm is chocolate I mean I guess you
巧克力有多热 我是说 我猜你
could have like a really desaturated
可能会像一个非常不饱和的
chocolate that's just very dark but I
很黑的巧克力 但我
think it's the more saturated is kind of
认为它越饱和 就越有可能
looks like milk chocolate like the kind
看起来像是牛奶巧克力
of delicious not the really super dark
美味的而不是真正的超级黑暗
stuff which I do actually like as an
我确实喜欢的东西作为一种
adult hated it as a kid but now I don't
大人小时候讨厌它 但现在我不讨厌了
know normal chocolate it's just way too
我知道普通巧克力 就是太棒了
sweet uh okay that now the top one H
太好了 好的 现在最上面的那个H
I'll make that one pink yeah that's fine
我要粉色的 好的 很好
and then this one I'll just make it blue
然后这个我就把它改成蓝色
icing and then this one I'll make it
涂上糖霜 然后这个我会做的
yellow icing oh wait now I've got the
黄色的结冰哦 等等 现在我得到了
yeah it's blue and blue and yellow and
是的 它是蓝色、蓝色和黄色的
yellow that's not good so this bottom
黄色的 那不好 所以这个底部
one no the middle one yeah middle one
一个不是中间的那个是的中间的那个
I'll make it chocolate bottom one I'll
我要做巧克力底的 我要
make it blue just trying to get like a
把它弄成蓝色只是想让它变得像
nice ah now I've got pink and pink next
很好啊 现在我有粉色和粉色了
to each other H all right maybe this one
H好的 也许是这一张
will be yellow as well that's too yellow
也会是黄色的 太黄了
all right maybe the bottom one can be
好的 也许最下面的一个
Pink There we go that's better all right
粉色的 我们去吧 这样好多了
so I don't have any like it now looks
所以我没有任何像现在这样的东西
more natural looks which is just more
看起来更自然 只是更
random I guess no less random cuz I'm
随机 我猜也不会减少 因为我是
like manually finessing it myself so
就像我自己手工打磨一样
it's less random but it looks uh more
它不那么随机 但看起来呃更多
random in a way anyway finally before we
不管怎样 在我们最后一次
move on let's start labeling our objects
让我们开始给我们的物品贴上标签吧
so first of all I want to make sure that
所以首先我想确保
my plane sorry my plate is inside of my
我的飞机 对不起 我的盘子在我的
environment collection so I will now
环境收藏 所以我现在就
call this plate this bottom one I will
这个盘子叫底盘 我就叫它底盘
call it uh yeah let call it counter and
叫它 呃 好的 让我们叫它柜台
then this back one I'll call it the
那么后面的这个我就叫它
backsplash
后挡板
awesome we have done it oh we do need to
太棒了 我们做到了 哦 我们确实需要
give a material to our plate as well
也给我们的盘子送一份材料
can't just have it as a default material
不能只将其作为默认材料
orse it'll look terrible so new material
否则它会看起来很可怕 所以是新材料
and the first thing I want to do is
我想做的第一件事是
adjust the roughness and make it look
调整粗糙度并使其看起来
kind of yeah shiny like the ceramic
是啊 像陶瓷一样闪闪发亮
plate let me just load that up actually
车牌 让我把它装上去
one more time there we go use that as my
再一次 我们用它作为我的
reference so it's somewhat shiny and
参考 所以它有点闪闪发亮
then also I want to give a subsurface
然后我还想给出一个次表面
because ceramic does actually have a
因为陶瓷实际上有一个
little bit of that um that creamy bleed
一点点那个奶油状的流血
through of the light so I'll turn my
穿过光芒 所以我会把我的
weight up to one radius all set to one
最大半径为1的权重均设置为1
and then the scale
然后是天平
01 so a very small amount of subsurface
所以只有很少量的地下
scattering um and it'll just help it a
散布嗯 这只会帮助它
little bit the color I'll also turn down
我也会把颜色调低一点
it to make it a little bit not so white
让它变得不那么白一点
and then I'll make it slightly yellow a
然后我会把它改成略带黄色的
little bit yellowy creamy color just
微微泛黄的奶油色
like over there
就像那边一样
if you want also you can buy the plate
如果你也想要的话 你可以买这个盘子
it's just not a free model but it will
这不是一个免费的模式 但它会的
add realism to your scene if you want to
如果您想要在场景中添加真实感
have a plate that is actually real and
有一个真正的车牌
photos scanned and it's got all these
扫描了照片 上面有所有这些
little speckled little things and divots
有斑点的小东西和草皮
across it if you want it is optional all
如果您想要的话 可以选择全部
right so that is it guys join me in the
好了 就这样吧 伙计们和我一起参加
next part and we're going to get into
下一部分 我们将进入
lighting I'll see you there
灯光照亮 我会在那里见到你